Justin Sybrandt

Ph.D. Student Email: Justin@Sybrandt.com Website: Justin.Sybrandt.com Phone: (484) 354-8692

About Me The power of machine learning (ML) has risen drastically over the last decade. Over time, we will likely see the growth of ML in all aspects of our lives, from health care to self-driving cars. I have begun to explore exciting new applications of ML in new domains such as medicine and civil engineering. I would like to help improve ML algorithms and extend them to new problems so they might do the most public good, and improve the quality of life for people worldwide.

Education

2016-Present, Clemson University

- Ph.D. in computer science. (GPA:4.0)
- Focus on machine learning, text mining, and literature-based discovery.

2012 - 2016, Grove City College

- BS in computer science, minor in mathematics.
- Graduated Summa Cum Laude with a GPA of 3.85.
- Top of class in computer science with a major GPA of 3.95.

Honors and Awards

- Recipient of the GAANN DAISE PhD. fellowship.
- Recipient of a KDD'17 travel award.
- Member of the Kappa Mu Epsilon National Mathematics Honor Society.
- Member of the Alpha Tau Mu chapter of Mortarboard.
- President of the Grove City Chapter of the ACM.

Papers and Presentations

MOLIERE: Automatic Biomedical Hypothesis Generation System

- Accepted for oral presentation at KDD 2017. (Acceptance Rate 8.8%)
- Awarded "Best Final Project and Poster Presentation" in Data Science student conference.
- Data mining 24.5 million medical documents to form a large multi-modal network.
- Models hypotheses using Latent Dirichlet Allocation.

Rapid Replication of Multi-Petabyte File Systems

- Presented at PDSW 2015 as a Work In Progress.
- Presented at the ACM student poster session at SC15.
- Built Distsync, a distributed tool capable of replicating large GPFS file systems.
- Deployed system with NERSC to facilitate large, high speed data transfers.

Development Skills and Technologies

C++
Python
Java
Bash
SQL
C
Scala
Julia
Linux
VIM
LaTeX
Git

Experience

Summer 2018, Incoming Intern, Google

• Will work in the advertising department to extend concepts from MOLIERE to understand how users interact with advertisements.

Summer 2017, Graduate Research Assistant - Los Alamos National Lab

- Developed high performance software in julia for non-negative matrix factorization.
- Extended MOLIERE to water resources research with the computational environmental science group (EES-16).

2015-2016, Programming Intern - Vigilant Cyber Systems, Inc.

- Developed a visualization library in Scala using ScalaFX.
- Independently managed time when working remotely.
- · Balanced senior-level course work with development.

Summer 2015, Student Researcher - UC Berkeley & NERSC

- Designed and implemented a tool to quickly synchronize multi-petabyte General Parallel File Systems.
- Presented a poster at the ACM Student Poster Session at SC'15.
- Presented a work in progress paper at the Parallel Data Storage Workshop.

Summer 2014, Student Researcher - Grove City College

- Added distribution preferences to Data Stream Management Systems (DSMS).
- Simulated new DSMS features in Python.
- Studied modern DSMS through recent research papers.
- Presented a poster at the Grove City student poster session.

2012-2014, Programming Intern - Gravic Inc.

- Worked on a six person team developing tools for administering exams.
- Collaborated with corporate partners to design features which allowed our products to share data.
- Gained familiarity with project management while extending the Remark VB.NET code base.

Research Interests

- Machine Learning
 Hypothesis Generation
 Big Data
- o Text Mining o Natural Language Understanding o Artificial Intelligence